ZARA RAHIMI

Vancouver, BC Linkedin.com/in/Zara-Rahimi • Github.com/Zara-Ra

PROFILE SUMMARY

Software developer with a bachelor's degree in Computer Engineering, demonstrating expertise in Java programming. Recognized as the top graduate of a coding bootcamp, acknowledged for teamwork, leadership, and time management. Committed to continuous learning and industry trend awareness.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Java SE/EE, Familiar with Python
- Spring Framework: MVC, Boot, Security, Data JPA, and Rest modules.
- Data Structures and Design Patterns
- Testing: Testing principles, including automated testing with JUnit, Selenium, Puppeteer
- API Testing: Postman for API testing
- Databases: PostgreSQL; Familiar with MongoDB (NoSQL)
- Front-End Technologies: Utilized JSON, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, jQuery, and AJAX.
- Docker: Exposure to Docker for containerization

EXPERIENCE

FAVOLAND - Vancouver, BC

Software Developer and Data Scraping Specialist

Contributed to the optimization of testing and data scraping processes.

- Developed and executed manual and automated Test Cases for User Stories, reducing defects.
- Identified and documented defects, contributing to faster issue resolution.
- Automated data scraping processes, expanding the company's database by 30%.
- Extracted details for 28,000 Amazon products, achieving an increase in data accuracy.
- Innovated a solution for converting ASIN to UPC, improving the barcode scanner feature, identifying 70% of UPC.

MAKTAB SHARIF - Tehran, Iran

Java Developer

Designed and implemented a Spring Boot RESTful API for the Home Service Application.

- Facilitated customer requests for various home services, improving customer satisfaction.
- Enabled experts to file offers for related orders, optimizing the order management system.
- Managed a team of 5, fostering a collaborative environment and contributing to team productivity.

VOLUNTEER

OpenBC - Vancouver, BC

Ian 2024- Now

Jul 2022-Mar 2023

Dec 2023- Now

Software Developer

Implementing the ingestion model as part of the Airbnb Regulation project to detect Airbnb listings that violate the short-term rental policy in British Columbia

CANADA LEARNING CODE - Vancouver, BC

Nov 2023- Now

Mentor

Empowering women and youth, to navigate the world of coding and fostering inclusivity in technology

EDUCATION

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Software Engineering, University of Tehran, Tehran, Iran

CERTIFICATES

Cloud Foundations - Linkedin Learing

Mar 2024

Agile Foundations - *Linkedin Learning* Java/Spring Coding Bootcamp - Tehran, Iran

Feb 2024 Mar 2023

• Completed a 400-hour practical course, graduated as the top student.